carlead.com 2005-02-08

# Privacy Policy | CarSmart

Carsmart.com understands your concern with privacy and the use of your personal information. Whether you submit a purchase request for a vehicle or simply browse through our Web site, we assure you that we are committed to protecting your personal privacy. 

 Carsmart.com. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for http://www.carsmart.com. If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact our Consumer Privacy Advocate by e-mail at ConsumerCare@carsmart.com, by phone at: 888-422-8999, Ext. 1387 or by mail at: 18872 MacArthur Blvd, Irvine, CA 92612. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns. 

Information Carsmart.com Collects 

Carsmart.com collects e-mail addresses of consumers who communicate with us via e-mail. Information on web pages visited and other information volunteered by consumers such as survey information and/or site registrations are also collected. Information collected for purchase requests includes name, address, and phone numbers, e-mail address and specific vehicle information. Information collected for private ad listings includes name, zip code, phone number, email address, specific vehicle information, and credit card information. 

Collected information is used to improve the content of our Web site, customize the content and/or layout of our Web site for individual users, notification of updates to our Web site and is also used to contact consumers for marketing purposes. Purchase request information is used to route requests to our accredited dealers, manufacturers and fulfillment partners, and to contact consumers regarding vehicle purchases. This information may be shared with other reputable organizations only if the consumer gives permission. For private ad listings, only the vehicle information is made available to potential buyers. When a potential buyer wishes to contact the seller, the seller receives a notice and logs in to the CarSmart.com website to view potential buyer's name, phone number and email address. Credit card information collected for the private ad listings is used solely for charging the listing fee and is shared only with the third party credit card processing company, Verisign CFX Tag. 

Who Owns Purchase Request Data? 

Purchase Request information, including your name, e-mail address, home address and vehicle information, becomes the property of Carsmart.com once it is received in our database. This information is passed on to our accredited dealers, manufacturers and fulfillment partners for completion of the sale pursuant to contractual rights granted by Carsmart.com. Once our accredited dealer receives this information, it becomes the property of the dealership in addition to Carsmart.com. Our accredited dealers use this information to process your purchase request and provide valuable services. Any request to opt out of future dealer communications must be made directly to the dealer. 

Personalization

Carsmart.com offers its users the advantage of personalization on our Web site by using cookies. (see Cookies) You will see this personalization in the "My Garage" area, in the saving of favorite vehicle information in "My Showroom", and used vehicle searches. Personalization in the "My Garage" area creates an individual experience for users by displaying the user's name and current vehicle information. 

If you use our used vehicle searches, our Web site will remember your login name. Our used car page will remember previous vehicle searches you have made. Web site personalization provides our customers with a more convenient online experience and is at no given time used to track information or retrieve data from your hard drive. 

Cookies

Carsmart.com offers consumers the convenience of online personalization by using cookies. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that are transferred to your computer's hard drive through your web browser. When this information is stored on your hard drive, our system is able to recognize your browser and in turn customize web page content for you. (See Personalization) 

Cookies cannot be used to retrieve data from your hard drive, obtain your e-mail address or obtain sensitive information about you. When a cookie is set, your browser will check it for length, an expiration date, and where it originated. Only Carsmart.com can access the cookies that we set. 

Carsmart.com allows our ad service company to set cookies as well. These cookies can "recognize" a consumer by a Unique identifier assigned at the time of the first visit, and may be used to measure site and page visits and browser version number. These cookies cannot obtain private information like name, e-mail or other personal information, and are not shared with Carsmart.com. 

We use a third party tracking service who sets cookies on our site to track visits, page views and click stream behavior. The third party tracking service reports this data to use in aggregate so we can better understand our users and to improve our site. This information is not tied to any individual user. 

If you prefer not to accept cookies, most browsers will explain how to disable cookies under the help portion of the toolbar or notify you when you receive a new cookie. However, if you choose to disallow cookies on your hard drive, our Web site will not be able to provide personalization services. 

Clear GIFs 

CarSmart.com uses clear GIFs to track user movement through the site for aggregated site traffic metrics. In addition, some CarSmart.com affiliates set Clear GIFs on our web pages to track completed Purchase Requests and Private Ad listings referred from their websites. 

Shared information 

Occasionally, when Carsmart.com does not have a member dealership available to assist our consumers we may forward your request information to a dealer at Autobytel.com or Autoweb.com, two other well-known online automotive referral services operated by Autobytel Inc. You will be notified that your information is forwarded at the time you submit your purchase request. At that time you will become subject to the security and privacy policies that are posted on those Web sites at www.autobytel.com, or www.Autoweb.com. If you have further questions about the Autobytel.com Privacy Policy you may contact Autobytel.com Customer Service at ConsumerCare@autobytel.com. For Autoweb.com please contact Autoweb customer service at ConsumerCare@autoweb.com. Other than as just described, Carsmart.com will not sell or rent your name, address or e-mail address to any third party without your permission. However, in situations where required by law, Carsmart.com may share this information in cooperation with law enforcement authorities. 

Outside Providers of Service 

Carsmart.com partners with outside service providers for some of the products and services offered. Certain of such partnerships are found on our Finance, Insurance and Warranty pages. The information these partners provide will be presented in a "framed" format, where the Carsmart.com border will surround the pages served by the partner.. 

Although Carsmart.com makes every attempt to work only with credible service provider partners, please be aware that you will be subject to these outside partners' security and privacy policies once you leave our Web site. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of these outside service providers, because their privacy practices may differ from ours. 

What Carsmart.com Tracks 

Carsmart.com tracks vehicle information entered into "My Garage" to provide service reminders and recall information, purchase request information and click-through information for e-mail sent to consumers. Purchase request data such as name, address and specific vehicle information is also tracked only for internal business and statistical purposes. 

Carsmart.com may track consumer interest in goods and services marketed to users who are members of the on-site personalization area. This information is used solely by Carsmart.com for business purposes. 

Browsing on our Web site 

If you browse through our Web site without entering any personal data, we will gather and store certain information about your visit. This information does not identify you personally and cannot be linked back to you unless you decide at some point to identify yourself. 

If you are only browsing, we collect the following information: IP address, the type of browser and operating system used to access our site, the date and time you access our site, the pages you visit (click-through), and if you linked to our Web site from another Web site, the address of that Web site. 

Privacy 

Any personal, identifiable information you submit to Carsmart.com will only be used with your permission. When submitting a purchase request on our Web site, you will be given the opportunity to choose which forms of communication you do or do not wish to receive from us by selecting check boxes. If you do not uncheck a box, consent is assumed to opt your e-mail address into the individual communication or service. (See E-mail Options) These options include service notifications and offers, newsletters, product offers from affiliate vendors that may be of interest to you and postal mail offers that may be of interest to you. Carsmart.com and its dealer partners will use phone numbers to contact customers regarding a purchase request for a vehicle. Additionally, phone numbers may be used to conduct customer surveys regarding individual experiences with Carsmart.com-dealer partners. Phone numbers are not sold to any third party. 

You always have the option of removing yourself from further e-mail contact. If at any time you choose to opt out of any offers, you can click on the remove link at the bottom of the e-mail offer. Or to opt yourself out of further contact email Customer Service at ConsumerCare@Carsmart.com with the word "Remove" in the subject line and we will remove you from e-mail and postal mail offerings within 5 business days. 

You may also make other corrections and updates to your personal information by contacting ConsumerCare@carsmart.com, or by accessing your settings in the "My Garage" personalized portion of our Web site by clicking on Log In on our Home Page. If you are already a member of "My Garage", you will be offered "My Settings" where you can make any adjustments you wish in your personally identifiable information, and e-mail settings. If you are not already a member of "My Garage", you will be invited to become a member and create your personal information and e-mail settings. 

If you choose to submit a Consumer Review of a Vehicle, you will be able to request that your name, e-mail address and a list of cars in your household be shown. If you do not give that permission, your personal information will not be displayed. 

If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you via e-mail. You will have a choice as to whether or not to allow us to use your information in this different manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying users of the change. In some cases we will also e-mail users who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices. 

Carsmart.com offers forums on its site. Please note that disclosing personally identifiable information online through Chat Rooms, Forums, and Message Boards makes the information submitted public, even though the forum is limited to registered members. Such disclosure may increase the chance of you receiving "spam" or unsolicited email. Be careful and use discretion when disclosing information online. 

Security

Carsmart.com understands the importance of security for our consumers. We use the latest SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption technology to protect personal data such as credit card information and finance or insurance application information during transmission. This allows your personal information to be submitted in a secure environment while reaching the intended parties. 

An SSL-capable web browser is needed to support this encryption technology. Netscape Navigator 4.6 or higher or Microsoft's Internet Explorer 4.01 or higher will support SSL technology. To verify that you are on a secure web page in Netscape Navigator, right-click while your cursor is on the form (not the border) and select "view Frame information" in Netscape Navigator. 

To view security certificates in Internet Explorer, click Internet Options on the View menu in the browser and then the Content tab. In the Certificates area, click the Personal, Sites, and Publishers buttons to view the current certificates. 

Other browsers may say "properties" or "page info". If the page is named https (Hyper Text Transfer Protocol Secure) instead of http, it is secure. 

Credit Card Data 

Credit Card data is collected by CarSmart.com for classified ad postings. CarSmart.com uses the latest SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology to protect your credit card information during transfer. (See Security) We do not release this information to any outside source. SSL is the Internet standard for secure transactions and is supported by Netscape Navigator 4.6 or higher and Microsoft Explorer 4.01 and higher. 

If you have any questions regarding your credit card data and how it is used, please contact our Consumer Privacy Advocate at 888-422-8999, Ext. 1387 or e-mail at ConsumerCare@carsmart.com. 

E-Mail Options

If you choose to opt in to all our offers, you can expect to receive various auto-related service and product e-mail from time to time. We understand that our customers may wish to be selective in opting out of specific offerings of products and services while retaining other services of interest. For those customers we provide the following options to choose which product and service offerings they receive: 

Log in to edit email options. 

Log in to edit email options.  

(Forgot your Zip? Click here) 

If you experience any difficulties in accessing this link or have any other questions or concerns regarding privacy, security, opting-out of e-mail offers or understanding how your e-mail address is being used, please contact our Consumer Privacy Advocate at 888-422-8999, Ext. 1387 or e-mail at ConsumerCare@carsmart.com. 

Contact Information 

If you have any questions, concerns or suggestions regarding our privacy and security policies, please contact our Consumer Privacy Advocate directly at 888-422-8999, Ext. 1387 or e-mail at ConsumerCare@autobytel.com. All issues will be handled in a timely manner.   
For any other issues, please contact our customer service department at ConsumerCare@carsmart.com. Our mailing address is: 18872 MacArthur Boulevard, Irvine, CA 92612-1400 

For the Carsmart.com Usage Terms and Conditions please click here. 

Effective Date: July 23, 2003
